Guide to the Helen and Kurt Wolff Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1903-1994; Series I; 18.97' (46 boxes)
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - Hinderer, Walter
      See: Princeton University, Box 36, folders 1085-1088
    - Hirschhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden, 1979 Nov 26 (Box 16, Folder 537)
    - Hirschmann, Ira [Arthur], 1983 Jan 3 (Box 16, Folder 538)
    - Hispanic Society of America, 1983 Mar 29 (Box 16, Folder 539)
    - Hodder and Stoughton, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 540)
    - Hofer, Evelyn, 1962, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 541)
    - Hofer, Philip, 1961-82 (Box 16, Folder 542)
    - Hoffmann und Campe, 1961-62 (Box 16, Folder 543)
    - Hoffmeister, Donna L., 1987 (Box 16, Folder 544)
    - Hölldobler, T., 1972-73 (Box 16, Folder 545)
    - Holsaert, James, 1959-62 (Box 17, Folder 546-553)
      Includes copy of letter to Bryher
    - Holsaert, James, 1962-89, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 554-559)
    - Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc., 1965 Aug (Box 17, Folder 560)
    - Homeyer, Fritz, 1962 May 17 (Box 17, Folder 561)
    - Horst, 1906-, 1982 Aug 23 (Box 17, Folder 562)
    - Hors'at Sefarim 'Am 'Oved, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 563)
    - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1960-91 (Box 17, Folder 564)
      See also: Lorenz, Konrad, Box 25, folders 772
    - House, Adrian, 1990-93, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 565)
      See also: Harvill Press, Box 15, folder 483 and Box 16, folder 503
    - Howe, Bruce, 1984 Jan 18 (Box 17, Folder 566)
    - Howe, Irving, 1959, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 567)
    - Howe, Quincy, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 568)
    - Huebsch, [B. W. (Benjamin W.)?], 1961 (Box 17, Folder 569)
    - Hughes, Olwyn, 1970-71, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 570)
    - Hull, Richard, 1960-66 (Box 17, Folder 571-572)
      Includes copies of letter to Hull from Aniela Jaffé
      See also: Sauerländer, Wolfgang, Box 38, folder 1176
    - Huntingford, George Wynn Brereton, 1964, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 573)
    - [Hutt?], Charles; [Hutt?], Betty, 1977-78, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 574)
    - Hyperion Verlag, 1962-63 (Box 18, Folder 575)
    - "I" General, 1959-85 (Box 18, Folder 576)
    - L'Indice dei Libri del Mese, 1988-89 (Box 18, Folder 577)
    - Insel-Verlag, 1960-64 (Box 18, Folder 578)
    - Instructor, [1985?] (Box 18, Folder 579)
    - Inter Nationes, 1982-93 (Box 18, Folder 580-580b)
    - International Rescue Committee, 1982-83, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 581)
    - Istituto Italiano di Cultura, 1982 Dec 15 (Box 18, Folder 582)
    - Istomin, Eugene, 1983-84 (Box 18, Folder 583)
    - Italia nostra (Association), 1973, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 584)
    - Ivask, Ivar, 1967, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 585)
    - Ivry, Alfred
      See: Zohn, Harry, Box 45, folder 1457
    - "J" General, 1974-91 (Box 18, Folder 586)
    - J. G. Cotta'sche Buchhandlung Nachfolger (Stuttgart, Germany), 1960-61 (Box 18, Folder 587)
    - Jacobi, Jolande Székacs, 1951-71, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 588-589)
    - Jaffé, Aniela, 1956-61 (Box 18, Folder 590-597)
      Includes copies of third-party correspondence with C.G. Jung, Richard Winston, and others
      See also: Hull, Richard, Box 17, folder 572 and Jung, Carl Gustav, Box 21, folder 658
    - Jaffé, Aniela, 1961-84, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 598)
    - Jahoda, Martin, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 599)
    - Jaspers, Karl, 1961-74, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 600-601)
    - Jauss, Anne Marie, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 602)
    - Jay, Martin, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 603)
    - Jerusalem International Book Fair, 1983 Nov 18 (Box 19, Folder 604)
    - The Jerusalem Quarterly, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 605)
    - Johannes-R.-Becher-Archiv, 1959-60 (Box 19, Folder 606)
    - John Murray (Firm), 1961-83 (Box 19, Folder 607-609)
      See also: Origo, Iris, Box 31, folder 971
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 610)
    - Johnson, Elisabeth, 1969-88 (Box 19, Folder 611)
    - Johnson, John, 1967 Jun (Box 19, Folder 612)
    - Johnson, Katharina, 1972, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 613)
    - Johnson, Uwe, 1965-84, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 614-616)
      Includes copy of letter to Johnson from Kay Boyle
    - Jonas, Klaus W., 1962-69 (Box 19, Folder 617)
      See also: Verlag Heinrich Scheffler, Box 43, folder 1355
    - Jonathan Cape Limited
      See: Origo, Iris, Box 31, folders 958-959
    - Jouhandeau, Marcel, 1925-60, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 618-619)
    - Jovanovich, Martha, 1988-91 (Box 19, Folder 620)
    - Jovanovich, William, 1961-75 (Box 19, Folder 621-624)
    - Jovanovich, William, 1975-77 (Box 20, Folder 625-632)
    - Jovanovich, William, 1977-79 (Box 20, Folder 633-640)
    - Jovanovich, William, 1979-89 (Box 21, Folder 641-648)
    - Jovanovich, William, 1990-94, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 649-650)
    - Jugoslavija, 1960-68, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 651-654)
    - Julian Back Literary Agency, 1982-83 (Box 21, Folder 655)
    - Julliard (Firm), 1981, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 656)
    - Junker, Jörg, 1962 Mar (Box 21, Folder 657)
    - Jung, C. G. (Carl Gustav), 1957-61, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 658)
      Includes copies of letters to the Bollingen Foundation, Aniela Jaffé, and Walter Niehus
      See also: Jaffé, Aniela, Box 18, folder 597
    - Jurgensen, Manfred, 1988-89 (Box 21, Folder 659)
    - Jurgrau, Thelma, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 660)
    - Juvelis, Priscilla, 1982 Oct 7 (Box 21, Folder 661)
    - "K" General, 1944-90, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 662)
    - Kahler, Erich; Kahler, Alice L., 1960-90, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 663)
    - Kandel, Michael, 1984-85 (Box 22, Folder 664)
      Includes reader reports on books by Stanislaw Lem
    - Kapelner, Alan, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 665)
    - Kapuscinski, Ryszard, 1983-87 (Box 22, Folder 666)
    - Karrer, Hans, 1958-60 (Box 22, Folder 667)
      Includes copies of letters from Karrer to Franz W. Beidler and C. G. Jung and contract
    - Karsunke, Yaak, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 668)
      Includes poem
    - [Kaschwitz, Marie Louise?], 1961, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 669)
    - Kaufman, Daniel, 1967-68 (Box 22, Folder 670)
    - Kelley, Robert Eaton, 1992-93 (Box 22, Folder 671)
    - Kenedy, Haidee, 1986-87 (Box 22, Folder 672)
    - Kern, Alfred, 1959-61, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 673)
    - Kerrigan, Anthony, 1961-62 (Box 22, Folder 674)
    - Kessler, Charles W. E, 1984-89 (Box 22, Folder 675)
    - Kielty, Bernardine, 1967 Aug 17 (Box 22, Folder 676)
    - Kienesberger, Konrad [Ferdinand], 1988 (Box 22, Folder 677)
    - Kiepenheuer & Witsch, 1962 (Box 22, Folder 678)
    - Killy, Walther, 1961-62 (Box 22, Folder 679)
    - Kindersley, Richard, 1979-80 (Box 22, Folder 680)
    - Kingsport Press, 1953-55 (Box 22, Folder 681)
    - Klarmann, Adolf D., 1961-63 (Box 22, Folder 682)
    - Kleine, Gisela, 1982-91 (Box 22, Folder 683)
    - Klemp, P. J., 1989 May 12 (Box 22, Folder 684)
    - Klett, Michael, 1981-89 (Box 22, Folder 685)
    - Knaus, Albrecht, 1964-66, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 686)
    - Knittel, Robert, 1960-86 (Box 22, Folder 687)
    - Knopf, Alfred A.
      See: Alfred A. Knopf, Box 1, folder 16
    - Koestler, Arthur, 1964-66, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 688)
    - Köhler, Lotte, 1980-88 (Box 22, Folder 689)
    - Konchellah, J. L. N. Ole, 1962-63 (Box 22, Folder 690)
    - Koning, Hans, 1978, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 691)
    - Koningsberger, Hans, 1965-66 (Box 22, Folder 692)
    - Konrád, György, 1982-90 (Box 22, Folder 693)
    - Kontextverlag, 1992-93 (Box 22, Folder 694)
    - Kösel-Verlag, 1962-67 (Box 22, Folder 695-696)
    - Kozlowski, Pawel, 1962-63 (Box 22, Folder 697)
    - Kpomassie, Tété-Michel, 1983 Sep 2 (Box 22, Folder 698)
    - Krafft von Dellmensingen, Ehrhart, 1968-86 (Box 22, Folder 699)
    - Krätzer, Anita, 1984-85 (Box 22, Folder 700)
    - Kraus Reprint Limited, 1967-68 (Box 22, Folder 701)
    - Krawehl, Ernst, 1989, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 702)
    - Kreisselmeier Verlag, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 703)
    - Kuehl, Linda, 1975-76 (Box 22, Folder 704)
    - Kuehnelt-Leddihn, Erik von, 1982 Nov 26 (Box 22, Folder 705)
    - Külz, Carla, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 706)
    - "L" General, 1948-93 (Box 23, Folder 707)
    - La Bruyère, Stacey de, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 708)
    - Lackner, Stephan, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 709)
    - The Ladies' Home Journal, 1960-62 (Box 23, Folder 710)
    - La Farge, Henry [Adams?], 1982 (Box 23, Folder 711)
    - Lall, Arthur [S. (Arthur Samuel)?], 1954 Apr 26 (Box 23, Folder 712)
    - Landshoff, Fritz-Helmut, 1982-83 (Box 23, Folder 713)
    - Lane, James, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 714)
    - Langewiesche, Wolfgang, 1961 (Box 23, Folder 715)
    - Lasky, Melvin J., 1978 Dec 5 (Box 23, Folder 716)
    - Lau, Estelle, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 717)
    - Laughlin, James
      See: New Directions Publishing, Box 30, folder 934
    - Lauterstein, Ingeborg, 1983 Aug 15 (Box 23, Folder 718)
    - Lawrence University, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 719)
    - Lecco, Alberto, 1983 Aug (Box 23, Folder 720)
    - Leeson, George, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 721)
    - Lerner, L. Scott, 1989 May 18 (Box 23, Folder 722)
    - Lettunichi, Mateo, 1981-83, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 723)
    - Levenson, Christopher, 1962-63 (Box 23, Folder 724)
    - Levin, Beatrice, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 725)
    - Levin, Nathan W., 1950-60, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 726-728)
      Includes copies of letters from Levin to John M. Lewis
      See also: Lewis, John M., Box 23, folder 731
    - Levy Enterprises, 1982, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 729)
    - Lewis, Dori, 1955 Apr 5 (Box 23, Folder 730)
    - Lewis, John M., 1949-60, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 731)
      Includes copy of letter from Lewis to Nathan W. Levin
      See also: Levin, Nathan W., Box 23, folders 726-728
    - Lewis, Norman, 1963-66, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 732)
    - Libération, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 733)
    - Librarie Plon, 1961-62 (Box 23, Folder 734)
    - Library of Congress, 1948-50 (Box 23, Folder 735)
    - Liepman, Ruth, 1961-93 (Box 23, Folder 736-737)
    - Liepmann, Klaus, n.y. Dec 1 (Box 23, Folder 738)
    - Lietzmann, Sabrina, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 739)
    - Life, 1954-69 (Box 23, Folder 740)
    - Lindbergh, Anne Morrow, 1953-60 (Box 23, Folder 741-744)
    - Lindbergh, Anne Morrow, 1960-69 (Box 24, Folder 745-752)
    - Lindbergh, Anne Morrow, 1969-74 (Box 24, Folder 753-760)
    - Lindbergh, Anne Morrow, 1974-90, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 761-764)
    - Lindbergh, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), 1957-82 (Box 25, Folder 765)
      Includes third-party correspondence
    - Lindbergh, Reeve, 1975-93, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 766)
    - Lindsay, Mrs. John, 1971 Nov (Box 25, Folder 767)
    - Liss, Andrea, 1985 Jun 17 (Box 25, Folder 768)
    - Long, Anton V., 1970 Nov (Box 25, Folder 769)
    - Longmans (Firm), 1966-67 (Box 25, Folder 770)
    - Loos, Anita, 1970-73, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 771)
      See also: Hayes, Helen, Box 16, folder 509
    - Lorenz, Konrad, 1964-73 (Box 25, Folder 772-779)
    - Lorenz, Konrad, 1973-89, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 780-784)
    - Los Angeles County Museum of Art, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 785)
    - Luchterhand Verlag, 1959-93, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 786-791)
    - Ludwig, Bernd, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 792)
    - Luke, David, 1967-72, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 793)
      Includes copy of letter to Luke from Keith Botsford
    - Lundeen, Ernst, 1989-90 (Box 26, Folder 794)
    - Lützeler, Paul Michael, 1980-85 (Box 26, Folder 795)
    - Lyons, Islay, 1954 May 19 (Box 26, Folder 796)
    - "M" General, 1959-91, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 797-798)
    - McCarthy, Mary, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 799)
      Includes copy of introduction to Marthe
    - McCormick, Ken, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 800)
    - McEwen, John
      See: Harvill Press, Box 14, folder 474
    - McFarland, Thomas L., 1984 Jun 22 (Box 26, Folder 801)
    - MacGibbon & Kee Ltd., 1963-67, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 802)
    - McGuire, William, 1951-85 (Box 26, Folder 803)
    - McMaster University, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 804)
    - McMurran, Carolyn, 1974, 1987 (Box 26, Folder 805)
    - McNeill, John J., 1964 (Box 26, Folder 806)
    - Magarshack, David, 1960 Feb (Box 26, Folder 807)
    - Mahler, Alma, 1922 (Box 26, Folder 808)
      Copies of letters from Mahler to Kurt Wolff
    - Mairesse, Thérèse, 1981-92 (Box 26, Folder 809)
    - Malamud, Bernard, 1981 Oct 26 (Box 26, Folder 810)
    - Mandel, Siegfried, 1982 (Box 26, Folder 811)
    - Manheim, Julia, 1992, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 812)
    - Manheim, Mary, 1974-76 (Box 26, Folder 813)
    - Manheim, Nora, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 814)
    - Manheim, Ralph, 1959-64 (Box 26, Folder 815-818)
      Includes letter from Harold Manheim and enclosures
    - Manheim, Ralph, 1964-71 (Box 27, Folder 819-826)
    - Manheim, Ralph, 1971-78 (Box 27, Folder 827-834)
    - Manheim, Ralph, 1978-92, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 835-839)
    - Mann, Michael, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 840-841)
    - Mann, Thomas; Mann, Erika, 1941-63, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 842-843)
      See also: Verlag Heinrich Scheffler, Box 43, folder 1356
    - Maraini, Fosco, 1963-70, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 844-846)
      Includes letter to Maraini from Alfred Bernheim
    - Mardersteig, Giovanni
      See: Stamperia Valdonega, Box 41, folders 1273-1275
    - Mardersteig, Irmi, 1978-83, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 847)
    - Marek, George [Richard?], 1981 May 29 (Box 28, Folder 848)
    - Mariano, Nicky, 1960-68, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 849-852)
    - Maritain, Jacques, 1947-53 (Box 28, Folder 853)
    - Marshack, Alexander, 1982 Nov 23 (Box 28, Folder 854)
    - Martin Gaite, Carmen, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 855)
    - Matthews, Jackson, 1954-57 (Box 28, Folder 856)
      See also: Bollingen Foundation, Box 2, folders 89-92
    - May, Derwent, 1985 Jun 25 (Box 28, Folder 857)
    - Mayer, Elizabeth, 1959-67, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 858-861)
    - Mayer, Hans-Otto, 1976 Jun 8 (Box 29, Folder 862)
    - [Mayer?], Lisa, 1972 Sep (Box 29, Folder 863)
    - Mayrock, Norbert, 1957 (Box 29, Folder 864)
    - Mazel, Ella, 1992 Mar 4 (Box 29, Folder 865)
    - Mehnert, Klaus, 1962 Apr (Box 29, Folder 866)
    - Mehring, Walter, 1960 (Box 29, Folder 867)
    - Mellon, Mary, 1943-46, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 868)
    - Mellon, Paul, 1958-59 (Box 29, Folder 869)
    - Mendelsohn, Aaron, 1984 (Box 29, Folder 870)
    - Mendelsohn, Anne, 1985 Oct 10 (Box 29, Folder 871)
    - Meneghello, Luigi, 1964, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 872)
    - Merck, George W., 1941-59 (Box 29, Folder 873)
      Includes correspondence with estate and enclsoures
    - Mercure de France (Firm), 1963-82 (Box 29, Folder 874)
    - Merton, Thomas, 1958-68, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 875)
      See also: Harvill Press, Box 14, folders 478-479
    - Meyer-Chagall, Ida, 1962 Mar 29 (Box 29, Folder 876)
    - Michael Karolyi Memorial Foundation, 1951, 1959 (Box 29, Folder 877)
    - Michael, Maurice, 1962-63 (Box 29, Folder 878)
    - Michaels, Kurt E., 1961 (Box 29, Folder 879)
    - Middeldorf, Ulrich [Alexander?], 1961 (Box 29, Folder 880)
    - Middleton, Christopher, 1964-67 (Box 29, Folder 881)
    - Milano, Paolo, 1962 (Box 29, Folder 882)
    - Milbouer, Staci A., 1986 (Box 29, Folder 883)
    - Milholland, James, 1976-85 (Box 29, Folder 884)
    - Miller, Henry, 1961-62 (Box 29, Folder 885)
    - Miller, Norbert, 1964 Apr 20 (Box 29, Folder 886)
    - Minor, Wendell, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 887)
    - Mitgang, Herbert, 1981-86, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 888)
      See also: Alfred A. Knopf, Box 1, folder 16
    - Mitscherlich, Alexander, 1963-66 (Box 29, Folder 889)
    - Mohrbooks, 1960-62 (Box 29, Folder 890)
    - Mohrt, Michel, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 891)
    - Molden, Fritz, 1966-67 (Box 29, Folder 892)
    - Molinaro, Ursule, 1966-67 (Box 29, Folder 893)
    - Mondor, Henri, 1951-52, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 894)
    - Monikova, Libuse, 1985-86 (Box 29, Folder 895)
    - Montagu, Ashley, 1966-67 (Box 29, Folder 896)
    - Moore, Marianne, 1968 Nov 26 (Box 29, Folder 897)
    - Moriconi, Virginia, 1962 (Box 29, Folder 898)
    - Morris, Elizabeth, 1961-83 (Box 29, Folder 899)
    - Morris, Jan, 1959-69 (Box 29, Folder 900-903)
    - Morris, Jan, 1969-93, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 904-906)
    - Morris, Suki, 1988-91 (Box 30, Folder 907)
    - Moss, Stanley, 1993 Oct 25 (Box 30, Folder 908)
    - Mossman, Elliott, 1978-87 (Box 30, Folder 909)
    - Mount Holyoke College, 1984 (Box 30, Folder 910)
    - Mueller, Lisel, 1982-85 (Box 30, Folder 911)
      Includes translations
    - Müftüoglu, Asuman U., 1982 Dec 17 (Box 30, Folder 912)
    - Müller, Ernst, 1948, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 913)
    - Müller, Gotthold, 1960 Oct (Box 30, Folder 914)
    - Mumford, Lewis, 1967 Apr 27 (Box 30, Folder 915)
    - Munroe, Afelia, 1988 (Box 30, Folder 916)
    - Muriaux, Christian, 1962, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 917)
    - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston
      See: Origo, Iris, Box 31, folder 961
    - Musson, Sydney A., 1930-31, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 918-921)
    - "N" General, 1960-92 (Box 30, Folder 922)
    - Nathan, Paul S., 1983 Nov 3 (Box 30, Folder 923)
    - The Nation, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 924)
      Includes copy of manuscript, "The Truth in Publishing," by Richard Kluger
    - National Endowment for the Arts (Box 30, Folder 925)
    - National Gallery of Art (U.S.)
      See: Cairns, Huntington, Box 3, folder 125
    - Navrozov, Andrei, 1982 Sep 17 (Box 30, Folder 926)
    - Neisser, Gerard E., 1960-61, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 927)
    - Nelson, Howard, 1961-67, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 928)
    - Neske Verlag, 1960-1992 (Box 30, Folder 929)
    - Neuhaus Volker, 1988-89 (Box 30, Folder 930)
    - Neumann, Bernd, 1988-92 (Box 30, Folder 931)
    - New American Library, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 932)
    - The New American Library of World Literature, Inc, 1959-60 (Box 30, Folder 933)
    - New Directions Publishing Corp., 1959-63 (Box 30, Folder 934)
    - The New Republic, 1953 Sep 10 (Box 30, Folder 935)
    - New School for Social Research (New York, N.Y.), 1985 Apr 26 (Box 30, Folder 936)
    - New York Herald Tribune, 1955, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 937)
    - New York (N.Y.). Police Dept., 1966-67 (Box 30, Folder 938)
    - New York Public Library, 1991 (Box 30, Folder 939)
    - New York Review of Books, 1966-85 (Box 30, Folder 940)
    - New York Times, 1959-90 (Box 30, Folder 941)
    - New York Times Book Review, 1955, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 942)
    - The New Yorker, 1953-84 (Box 30, Folder 943)
    - Newsweek, 1953 Jul 27 (Box 30, Folder 944)
    - Niehus, Walther, 1960-61 (Box 30, Folder 945)
      Includes copies of letters from Niehus to Aniela Jaffé, Rascher Verlag, and Routledge
      See also: Jung, Carl Gustav, Box 21, folder 658
    - 92nd Street Y (New York, N.Y.), 1975 Oct 10 (Box 30, Folder 946)
    - Noguchi, Isamu, 1958, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 947)
    - Noll, Bink, 1982 (Box 30, Folder 948)
    - Norman, Dorothy, 1953-90 (Box 31, Folder 949-950)
    - Novak, Frank R., 1972-75 (Box 31, Folder 951)
    - Nowak, Ernestine, 1981-82 (Box 31, Folder 952)
    - "O" General, 1959, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 953)
    - Oakes, Maud, 1965, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 954)
    - O'Brien, Justin, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 955)
    - Origo, Iris, 1952-63 (Box 31, Folder 956-963)
      Includes third-party correspondence with Stamperia Valdonega, Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, John Murray (Firm), Jonathan Cape Limited, David Godine, and others
    - Origo, Iris, 1963-82 (Box 31, Folder 964-971)
    - Origo, Iris, 1982-88, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 972-976)
    - Origo Verlag, 1961-62 (Box 32, Folder 977)
    - Osterle, Heinz D., 1985-88 (Box 32, Folder 978)
      Includes copies of reviews
    - Österreichische Nationalbibliothek, 1960 Jun 27 (Box 32, Folder 979)
    - Otten, Ellen, 1964-93, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 980-981)
    - Otto Müller Verlag, 1961 Oct (Box 32, Folder 982)
    - Overlook Press, 1981 Jun 24 (Box 32, Folder 983)
    - Owen, Deborah
      See Oz, Amos, Box 32, folders 984-987
    - Oz, Amos, 1973-90, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 984-987)
      Includes copies of Harcourt memos and correspondence with Deborah Owen, B'nai B'rith, Harriet Rochlin, Gerald Gross, and others
    - "P" General, 1954-93, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 988)
    - Page, Chester [Hall?], 1994 Mar 8 (Box 32, Folder 989)
    - Pan American Airways Corporation, 1980 Oct 21 (Box 32, Folder 990)
    - Panofsky, Erwin, 1951-65, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 991-993)
      Includes copies of letters from Panofsky to Bollingen Foundation and enclosures
    - Pantheon Books, 1945-59 (Box 33, Folder 994-1001)
    - Pantheon Books, 1959 (Box 33, Folder 1002-1009)
    - Pantheon Books, 1959-60 (Box 33, Folder 1010-1013)
    - Pantheon Books, 1960 (Box 34, Folder 1014-1021)
    - Pantheon Books, 1960, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1022-1025)
    - Pantheon Books (external), 1961-85, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1026)
    - Paoli, Pia, 1967-68 (Box 34, Folder 1027)
    - Pape, Matthias, 1987 (Box 34, Folder 1028)
    - Paris-Match, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 1029)
    - Partisan Review, 1953 Nov (Box 34, Folder 1030)
    - Pasternak, Boris Leonidovich, 1958-60, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1031-1034)
      Includes transcriptions of letters
    - Pasternak, E. B. (Evgenii Borisovich), 1985 Mar 15 (Box 34, Folder 1035)
    - Pasternak, Zh. (Zhozefine Leonidova), 1961-67 (Box 34, Folder 1036)
    - Paul List Verlag, 1957 May (Box 34, Folder 1037)
    - Paul, Weiss, Rifkind, Wharton & Garrison, 1960 Mar (Box 34, Folder 1038)
    - Paul Zsolnay Verlag, 1962 Sep (Box 34, Folder 1039)
    - Paulding, Gouverneur, 1966 Dec (Box 34, Folder 1040)
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1959-73, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1041-1042)
    - Pelet, Emma von, 1937-49, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1043)
    - Pelikan, Maria, 1982-92 (Box 35, Folder 1044)
    - Penguin (Firm), 1967-88 (Box 35, Folder 1045)
    - Percy Lund, Humphries & Co. Ltd., 1957-59 (Box 35, Folder 1046)
    - Performing Arts Journal, 1983 Jan 20 (Box 35, Folder 1047)
    - Petrarch Press, 1990 (Box 35, Folder 1048)
    - Peyer, Bernhard, 1960-63, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1049-1050)
      See also: William Collins Sons & Co., Box 44, folder 1422
    - Peyre, Henri, 1953 (Box 35, Folder 1051)
    - Pfeiffer, Ernst, 1962-86 (Box 35, Folder 1052-1055)
    - Philipp, Claudia Gabriele, 1982 Feb 23 (Box 35, Folder 1056)
    - Phoebus-Verlag, 1962-63, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1057)
    - Pieper, Josef, 1960-92, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1058-1061)
    - Pignatti, Terisio, 1963 (Box 35, Folder 1062)
    - Pilling, Iris, 1990, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1063)
    - Pinthus, Kurt, 1962 (Box 35, Folder 1064)
    - Piper, Klaus, 1960 Jul 29 (Box 35, Folder 1065)
    - Pins, Jacob, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 1066)
    - Piper Verlag, 1974-93 (Box 35, Folder 1067-1069)
    - Piron, Maurice, 1985 (Box 35, Folder 1070)
    - Pitkin, Donald S., 1982 (Box 35, Folder 1071)
    - Plaas, Rudolf, 1984-89, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1072)
    - Plimpton Press, 1953-54 (Box 35, Folder 1073)
    - Plyushch, Leonid, 1976 Apr 10 (Box 35, Folder 1074)
    - Pocket Theatre, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1075)
    - Pollock & Stein
    - Poetry Center of the 92nd Street YM-YMHA (New York, N.Y.), 1967-88, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1076)
    - Powers Engraving Co., 1953-54 (Box 35, Folder 1077)
    - Politzer, Heinz, 1961 Oct 25 (Box 35, Folder 1078)
    - Praesent, Angela, 1988 (Box 35, Folder 1079)
    - Preetorius, Emil, 1909-46, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1080-1081)
    - Prescott, Peter S., 1974, 1979 (Box 36, Folder 1082)
    - Presses de la Cité, 1965-67 (Box 36, Folder 1083)
    - Prestel Verlag, 1963-66, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1084)
    - Princeton University Department of Germanic Languages and Literatures Advisory Council, 1978-81, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1085-1088)
      Includes correspondence with Michael Curschmann, Walter Hinderer, Hans Rosenhaup, and Theodore Ziolkowski
    - Princeton University. Library, 1965 (Box 36, Folder 1089)
    - Princeton Univeristy Press, 1981 (Box 36, Folder 1090)
    - Publishers' Lunch Club, 1982-92 (Box 36, Folder 1091)
    - Quine, W. V. (Willard Van Orman), 1964 (Box 36, Folder 1092)
    - "R" General, 1953-93, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1093-1094)
    - Random House (Firm), 1958 Oct 23 (Box 36, Folder 1095)
    - Rascher Verlag, 1952-66 (Box 36, Folder 1096)